二零二二年普通高等学校招生
will Before Now is the listening test time.
全国统一考试英语科听力部分第二次考试。该部分分为第一、第二两节。注意，回答听力部分。本时，请先将答案标在试卷上。听力部分结束前，你将有两分钟的时间将你的答案转涂到答题卡上。
I read about your club in the paper today, and I thought I'd phone to find out a bit
more. Yes, certainly.
Well, we're a sort of social club for people from different countries.
It's quite a new club.
We have about 50 members at the moment, but we're growing all the time.
That sounds interesting.
I'm British, actually, and I came to Washington about three months ago.
I'm looking for ways to meet people.
Er, what kinds of events do you organize?
Well, we have social get -togethers and sports events, and we also have language
evenings. Could you tell me something about the language evenings?
Yes. Every day except Thursday, we have a language evening.
People can come and practice their languages, you know, over a drink or something.
We have different languages on different evenings.
Monday, Spanish, Tuesday, Italian, Wednesday, German, and Friday, French.
On Thursday, we usually have a meal in a restaurant for anyone who wants to come.
Well, that sounds great.
I really need to practice my French.
Okay. Well, if you can just give me your name and address, I'll send you the form
and some more information.
If you join now, you can have the first month free.
试音到此结束。听力考试正式开始。请看听力部分第一节。第一节。听下面五段对话，每段对话后有一个小题。从题中所给的三个选项中选出最佳选项。听完每段对话后，你都有十秒。秒钟的时间来回答有关小题和阅读下一小题。每段对话仅读一遍。例如，现在你有五秒钟的时间看试卷上的例题。你将听到以下内容。
Excuse me, can you tell me how much the shirt is?
Yes, it's 9.15.
你将有五秒钟的时间将正确答案标在试卷上。衬衫的价格为九磅十五便士，所以你选择项，并将其标在试卷上。现在，你有五秒钟的时间阅读。读第一小题的有关内容。
Did you watch the show yesterday afternoon?
No, I was busy with my report.
Did you watch it?
Yes, I went with my cousin.
It was quite good.
Hi, Albert. I just received a call from Peterson's company.
They want to know if the brochures are ready.
Well, the printing has been delayed because the factory went through a power failure
the other day.
Excuse me, where are the check -in desks for American Airlines?
Over there. Desks numbers 47 to 50.
Okay, thanks. Steve, what would you say is your hometown?
Um, that's a difficult question because I've traveled around so much.
Still, um, Toronto I suppose.
I've lived there for more than 20 years.
I wasn't born there though.
Look at all the paper in the wastebasket next to the copy machine.
That's really wasteful.
There should be a better way to deal with it.
Well, we should try to recycle all our waste paper.
That would save money and help the environment.
第一节到此结束。第二节。听下面五段对话或独白。每段对话或独白后有几个小题，从题中所给的三个选项中选出最佳选项。听每段对话或独白。来前，你将有时间阅读各个小题，每小题五秒钟。听完后，各小题将给出五秒钟的作答时间。每段对话或独白读两遍。听下面一段对话，回答第六和第七两个小题。现在你有十秒钟的时间阅读这两个小题。
Who was that?
It was Cindy.
She sounded very upset and said that she couldn't follow the teacher.
I knew the training class was making her upset.
Honey, calm down.
She'll be all right.
I'm calling her teacher.
Give me Miss Gail's number.
Maybe she could help her.
Okay, okay. Her number is 673 -898 -98.
Who was that?
It was Cindy.
She sounded very upset and said that she couldn't follow the teacher.
I knew the training class was making her upset.
Honey, calm down.
She'll be all right.
I'm calling her teacher.
Give me Miss Gail's Maybe she could help her.
Okay, okay. Her number is 673 -898 -98.
you. Lucy, I have a conflict in my schedule.
听下面一段对话，回答第八至第十三个小题。现在你有十五秒钟的时间阅读这三个小题。
I don't know what to do.
Can't you rearrange your schedule?
No. The other sections of the courses I need are closed.
Then you'll have to a
I don't know which one to drop.
Math 102 or History 301?
Well, since you want to in computer science and you need to take Math 102 before
taking several computer science courses, like CS203, it's important to take Math 102
right away. You are right.
But I do like history, and I heard the history teacher is a very good one.
I'll think about it.
Lucy, I have a conflict in my schedule.
I don't know what to do.
Can't you rearrange your schedule?
No. The other sections of the courses I need are closed.
Then you'll have to a
I don't know which one to drop.
Math 102 or History 301?
Well, since you want to in science and you need to take Math 102 before taking
several computer science courses, like CS203, it's important to take Math 102 right
away. You are right.
But I do like history, and I heard the history teacher is a very good one.
I'll think about it.
听下面一段对话，回答第十一至第十三三个小题。现在你有十五秒钟的时间阅读这三个小题。
Hey, you're back from your vacation.
Where did you go?
Mattyville. Where is Mattyville?
I've never heard of it.
It's a small town, about a six -hour drive from here.
There is an old -style Main Street, just like one in the good old days, you know?
It was really amazing.
Along the street there are many old shops, and the people are very friendly.
I'm not sure I'd want to travel back in time.
It doesn't sound very exciting.
It was not as lively as some places I had been to, but I enjoyed the old shops, the
sincere people, and the true friendliness.
What did you do there?
For an entire week, I visited the shops, ate at the family -owned restaurants,
and learned about the unusual history of the town by chatting with the old -timers
at the local bar.
But that sounds like a boring place to me.
Then I guess you wouldn't want to go back with me this summer for their music
festival. Did you say music festival?
Maybe I shouldn't dismiss small -town appeal quite so quickly.
Hey, you're back from your vacation.
Where did you go?
Mattyville. Where is Mattyville?
I've never heard of it.
It's a small town, about a six -hour drive from here.
There is an old -style main street, just like one in the good old days, you know?
It was really amazing.
Along the street there are many old shops, and the people are very friendly.
I'm not sure I'd want to travel back in time.
It doesn't sound very exciting.
It was not as lively as some places I had been to, but I enjoyed the old shops, the
sincere people, and the true friendliness.
What did you do there?
For an entire week, I visited the shops, ate at the family -owned restaurants, and
learned about the unusual history of the town by chatting with the old -timers at
the local bar.
But that sounds like a boring place to me.
Then I guess you wouldn't want to go back with me this summer for their music
festival. Did you say music festival?
Maybe I shouldn't dismiss small -town appeal quite so quickly.
听下面一段对话，回答第十四至第十七四个小题。现在你有二十秒钟的时间阅读这四个小。题。
Did you enjoy your stay with us, sir?
Yes, very much.
Now I need to get to the airport.
I have a flight that leaves in about two hours.
I heard you have a free airport bus service?
Yes, we do.
The next bus leaves in about half an hour.
It takes about 25 minutes to get to the airport.
Fantastic. I'll just wait in the hallway.
Will you please let me know when it will be leaving?
Of course, sir.
Oh, before you go, would you please settle the bill for your drink at our bar just
now? Oh, sorry.
I almost forgot.
How much is it?
$15.50. How would you like to pay?
Credit card. And I'll need a receipt, please.
Okay. Would you like to sign the hotel guestbook while you wait?
Sure. I had a really good stay here.
Thank you again for staying with us.
Did you enjoy your stay with us,
Yes, very much.
Now I need to get to the airport.
I have a flight that leaves in about two hours.
I heard you have a free airport bus service?
Yes, we do.
The next bus leaves in about half an hour.
It takes about 25 minutes to get to the airport.
Fantastic. I'll just wait in the hallway.
Will you please let me know when it will be leaving?
Of course, sir.
Oh, before you go, would you please settle the bill for your drink at our bar just
now? Oh, sorry.
I almost forgot.
How much is it?
$15.50. How would you like to pay?
Credit card. And I'll need a receipt, please.
Okay. Would you like to sign the hotel guestbook while you wait?
Sure. I had a really good stay here.
Thank you again for staying with us.
听下面一段独白，回答第十八至第二十三个小题。现在你有十五秒钟的时间阅读这三个小题。
Well, now let me tell you what I've been doing in recent years.
In 2015, I retired from my post as a designer for a furniture company.
And since then, I've been working as a volunteer.
In 2017, I joined Green Woodpecker,
an organization that promotes environmental protection.
At the beginning, I mostly worked in public squares near the West Railway Station.
Helping the traffic police and giving directions to passengers.
my work focus changed.
When our city adopted the new tobacco control rules in June 2018,
I began a new task.
Persuading people not to smoke in public places.
In addition to the railway station, I have been going to places where there are many
restaurants and bars.
We work in groups of and try to stop people from smoking.
Fortunately, most smokers are supportive and put out their cigarettes when we ask
them to. But that was not the case in the early days.
Some smokers could become quite violent.
I like being a volunteer.
The work is exciting and makes me feel young.
It has now become part of my life.
Well, now let me tell you what I've been doing in recent years.
In 2015, I retired from my post as a designer for a furniture company.
And since then, I've been working as a volunteer.
In 2017, I joined Green Woodpecker, an organization that promotes environmental
protection. At the beginning, I mostly worked in public squares near the West
Railway Station, helping the traffic police and giving directions to passengers.
Then my work focus changed.
When our city adopted the new tobacco control rules in June 2018,
I began a new task.
Persuading people not to smoke in public places.
In addition to the railway station, I have been going to places where there are many
restaurants and bars.
We work in groups of and try to stop people from smoking.
Fortunately, most smokers are supportive and put out their cigarettes when we ask
them to. But that was not the case in the early days.
Some smokers could become quite violent.
I like being a The work is exciting and makes me feel young.
It has now become part of my life.
第二节到此结束。现在你有两分钟的时间。将试卷上的答案转涂到答题卡上。
Thank you for watching.
Thank you. you
听力部分第二次考试到此结束。